

(817) 694-2015 hello@staffordrose.com github.com/staffordrose

Front-end web developer with 4+ years of experience building web applications. I am self-taught and worked as the sole designer and developer of multiple user-facing React applications.

The years I spent with Leisure Time Inc. were incredible and illuminating. I explored my interests, discovered my passion for web development, and gained valuable experience designing and developing JavaScript applications. However, after years as a solo programmer, I felt that I would benefit from joining an established dev team. After planning my departure with management and training my replacement, I left Leisure Time and learned technologies that I used to build my portfolio and become a more well-rounded front-end dev. I'm now seeking to join an engineering team where I can make an impact and continue to grow as a developer.

Work Experience

Web Developer

Jan 2018 - Feb 2022

Leisure Time Inc. - Idaho Falls, ID

Worked remotely as sole designer and developer of hot tub/hearth product configurator, customer portal, employee dashboard, headless Shopify storefront, public website, and internal component library. Interfaced with ownership and department heads to ensure the products met desired outcomes.

- Built customer portal with product configurator
- Built employee dashboard with quote builder
- Built headless Shopify storefront
- Migrated WordPress site to Next.js & Prismic
- Refactored product configurator/quote builder into standalone package
- Developed inbound/outbound email service using Cloud Run & Postmark
- Authored shared component library to unify design language of websites

② Letter of Recommendation available upon request

Videographer

May 2015 - Dec 2017

Independent Contractor - Salt Lake City, UT

- Filmed & edited promotional videos for:
- Montana Fly Fishing Guides Livingston, MT
- Fly Fish Rockport Rockport, TX
- Leisure Time Inc. Idaho Falls. ID
- Filmed & edited local TV commercial for Leisure Time Inc. Idaho Falls, ID
- Filmed & edited weddings in Utah & Texas

Work Experience (continued)

Internet Marketing Consultant

Apr 2014 - Dec 2017

Independent Contractor - Provo & Salt Lake City, UT

Worked for a few local businesses in Idaho, Montana, and Texas. More than 60% of my billable hours were for Leisure Time Inc.

- Built & updated WordPress websites
- Created & managed AdWords campaigns for clientele
- Claimed local directories & updated client info
- Prepared SEO audits & implemented optimizations
- Designed web graphics for promotional banners, display ads & email newsletters
- Designed print graphics for business cards, vehicle wraps & product signage

Internet Marketing Guru

May 2013 - Apr 2014

High 5 Promotions - Austin, TX

- Created & managed AdWords campaigns for clientele
- Claimed local directories & updated client info
- Prepared SEO audits & implemented optimizations
- Updated content & design of client WordPress sites

Internet Marketing Intern

Oct 2012 - May 2013

High 5 Promotions - Austin, TX

- Created & managed AdWords campaigns for clientele
- Claimed local directories & updated client info
- Prepared SEO audits & implemented optimizations
- Updated content & design of client WordPress sites

Education

Texas State University-San Marcos

Fall 2011 - Spring 2013

Bachelor of Business Administration - Marketing

- Graduated May 2013
- Texas State GPA: 3.9/4.0
- American Marketing Association National Case Competition Team (2nd place)
- Completed generals at Weatherford College & Austin Community College prior to attending TXST

Skills

- Detail-oriented
- Problem solving
- Teamwork
- Self-management
- Communication skills
- Strategic planning

Interests

- Canyoneering
- Cycling
- Fly fishing
- Hiking
- Camping
- Skiing